VIDYA KAIPA

Address

3125 Lewiston Ave. Berkeley, CA 94705

Tel 408-230-4570

Em vidyalkaipa@gmail.com

Url www.pocketgypsy.wordpress.com www.vidyakaipa.wordpress.com

What You Need To Know About Vidya

Vidya is a big thinker with an inquisitive mind and boundless energy. Her passion for social impact and equality is an integral and clearly-articulated part of both her personality and career objectives. Her core strengths include business analytics, content and design, and program strategy. She seeks a vibrant, creative work environment with ambitious, innovative, and well-traveled coworkers. (She does not commonly reference herself in the third person.)

Business development	Content / design	Market research

Work History

MentorCloud | San Francisco, CA | October 2013 - Present

Marketing and Design Analyst: Create and manage MentorCloud's marketing strategy. Provide input on product development. Develop case studies, white papers, and comparative analytics. Oversee all external messaging. Design graphics and provide photographs. Redesign and edit website content and visuals.

Runway | San Francisco, CA | January 2014 - January 2015 **Program Manager:** Developed programming (workshops, lectures, panels, etc.) around community-defined subject- matter interests. Designed, curated, coordinated, and marketed educational events held at Runway's coworking space. Created artistic documentation and new methods of spreading marketing collateral to community.

Mastek | Mumbai, India | June 2012 - March 2013
Researcher: Authored reports on economic philosophy, international governments, and structural change for CEO Sudhakar Ram. Contributed research to *The New Constructs*, a book now in editorial review. Worked remotely.

Go Overseas | Berkeley, CA | January 2012 - May 2012 **Chief Content Editor:** Organized, edited, and published all article content for Go Overseas, a programs-abroad web startup. Created and managed editorial calendar, oversaw subject matter and quality of written copy, created interactive spreadsheets for managing published content, maintained relationships with contributors and partners.

Go Overseas | Berkeley, CA | September 2011 - December 2011 **Marketing and Editorial Intern**: Wrote article content and program listings, researched article-related projects, structured new article silos.

George Beier Campaign for City Council | Berkeley, CA | May 2010 - November 2010 Treasurer, Office Manager and Photographer: Maintained contributions and expenses for George Beier and Gordon Wozniak. Maintained relationships with key donors and campaign contributors, balanced budget, photographed events and prepared campaign material, assisted with office work.

Education

University of California, Berkeley

Political Science and Sociology GPA (combined): 3.5 August 2008 - May 2012

University of Cambridge

Thesis: "Why Youth Don't Vote: A Social and Political Survey" June 2011 - August 2011

Skills



- Adobe Lightroom
- Adobe Photoshop
- Bohemian Code Sketch
- DSLR Photography (Canon)
- Familiar with Adobe InDesign



- Microsoft Word, Excel, Powerpoint
- Wordpress
- MailChimp
- Google Analytics
- Google AdWords
- Hotjar
- Optimizely



- Conversational Spanish
- Conversational Telugu
- Comfortable with SEO
- Insightly
- Improvisational Speaker